<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Harmony</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/</link><description>Recent content on Harmony</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:05:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harmonydata.github.io/website/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FAIR Data</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/fair-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 14:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/fair-data/</guid><description>What are the FAIR Data Principles? The FAIR principles are a set of guidelines for making data more discoverable, accessible, interoperable, and reusable. The principles are intended to help organizations and individuals maximise the value of their data by making it easier to find, access, and use.
The FAIR principles were published in Nature in 2016 to address the difficulties in reproducing scientific research. Funding organisations, publishers, and governmental agencies are increasingly beginning to require data management plans for data generated in research.</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/frequently-asked-questions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 12:33:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/frequently-asked-questions/</guid><description>What is harmonisation? Harmonisation means taking variables from different studies and manipulating them to make them comparable.
For example, if we have datasets of depression from different countries, which is typically measured using a questionnaire, how can we harmonise two depression questionnaires? Typically this is a manual process – we would look at the content and find common elements between the questionnaires.
For an example of a pre-existing harmonisation tool, please see:</description></item><item><title>harmony Privacy Policy</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:33:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/privacy-policy/</guid><description>Our contact details harmonydata.org is provided by Ulster University.
The Office of the University Secretary is the data controller for harmonydata.org. A data controller determines how and why personal data is processed.
What data we collect The personal data we collect from you may include the following:
questions, queries or feedback you leave, including your email address if you contact us or sign up to our email alerts your name telephone numbers how you use our emails – for example whether you open them and which links you click on your Internet Protocol (IP) address, and details of which version of web browser you used information on how you use the site, using cookies and page tagging techniques Third party cookies We use third party cookies, including Google Analytics, to collect information about how you use harmonydata.</description></item><item><title>Team</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/team/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 23:08:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/team/</guid><description>The Harmony team The team working on Harmony was made up of: Dr. Eoin McElroy Lecturer in Psychology at the University of Ulster, Northern Ireland
Dr. Bettina Moltrecht Research Fellow in Population Health and Quantitative Social Science at University College London
Prof. George Ploubidis Professor of Population Health and Statistics at the Social Research Institute at University College London
Dr. Mauricio Scopel Hoffmann Associate Professor in the Department of Neuropsychiatry at Universidade Federal de Santa Maria, Brazil</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 07:27:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/contact/</guid><description>Contact Harmony Please fill out the form and we will get back to you as soon as possible. SUBMIT</description></item><item><title>Projects &amp;#038; Partners</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/projects-partners/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 06:55:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/projects-partners/</guid><description>Harmonising mental health data We are excited to announce that we are working on a new project called Harmony for the Wellcome Trust Mental Health Data Prize – Harmony will use natural language processing to help us with comparing measures and data collected with these measures across multiple studies. In most social and psychological research different questionnaires are used, such as the GAD-7 and Beck’s Anxiety Inventory, to assess people’s mental health, these questionnaires are also available indifferent languages and have been used in various countries across the world!</description></item><item><title>Harmony</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/harmony/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 12:11:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/harmony/</guid><description>harmony Harmonising Mental Health Data Do you need to compare questionnaire data across studies? Do you want to find the best match for a set of items? Are there are different versions of the same questionnaire floating around and you want to make sure how compatible they are? Are the questionnaires written in different languages that you would like to compare?
Harmony is a data harmonisation project that uses Natural Language Processing to help researchers make better use of existing data from different studies by supporting them with the harmonisation of various measures and items used in different studies.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 15:36:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/about/</guid><description>May the Force be with you, the Torque about you This is where my great about goes</description></item></channel></rss>