<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technical on Harmony</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/categories/technical/</link><description>Recent content in Technical on Harmony</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 22:36:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harmonydata.github.io/website/categories/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Semantic text matching with deep learning Transformer models</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-02-08-semantic-text-matching-with-deep-learning-transformer-models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 22:36:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-02-08-semantic-text-matching-with-deep-learning-transformer-models/</guid><description>Semantic text matching is a task in natural language processing involving estimating the semantic similarity between two texts. For example, if we had to quantify the similarity between “I feel nervous” and “I feel anxious”, most people would agree that these are closer together than either sentence is to “I feel happy”. A semantic text matching algorithm would be able to place a number on the similarity, such as 79%.</description></item><item><title>Measuring the Performance of NLP algorithms</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-12-03-measuring-the-performance-of-nlp-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 01:19:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-12-03-measuring-the-performance-of-nlp-algorithms/</guid><description>Harmony was able to reconstruct the matches of the questionnaire harmonisation tool developed by McElroy et al in 2020 with the following AUC scores: childhood 84%, adulthood 80%. Harmony was able to match the questions of the English and Portuguese GAD-7 instruments with AUC 100% and the Portuguese CBCL and SDQ with AUC 89%. Harmony was also evaluated using a variety of transformer models including MentalBERT, a publicly available pretrained language model for the mental healthcare domain.</description></item><item><title>How does Harmony work?</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-03-how-does-harmony-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 14:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-03-how-does-harmony-work/</guid><description>When you input two questionnaires into Harmony, such as the GAD-7 and Beck’s Anxiety Inventory, Harmony is able to match similar questions and assign a number to the match. (I have written another blog post on how we measured Harmony’s performance in terms of AUC).
So how does Harmony achieve this?
Harmony uses techniques from the field of natural language processing to identify when two questions deal with a similar topic.</description></item></channel></rss>