<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Harmony</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Harmony</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:05:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sign up to test Harmony</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-06-28-sign-up-to-test-harmony/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-06-28-sign-up-to-test-harmony/</guid><description>We are running workshops to test Harmony – see the signup link here.</description></item><item><title>Survey: What features would you like to see in Harmony?</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-04-20-what-features-would-you-like-to-see-in-harmony/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 14:13:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-04-20-what-features-would-you-like-to-see-in-harmony/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Radio podcast about Wellcome Data Prize</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-03-25-radio-podcast-about-wellcome-data-prize/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 20:57:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-03-25-radio-podcast-about-wellcome-data-prize/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Harmony going forward</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-03-10-harmony-going-forward-5-things-implementation-science-has-taught-us-to-focus-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 14:31:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-03-10-harmony-going-forward-5-things-implementation-science-has-taught-us-to-focus-on/</guid><description>5 key things Implementation Science has taught us to focus on
Yesterday the Harmony team received the wonderful news that we are given the chance to continue working on Harmony for another six months, after which we can put ourselves forward for the final round. The Wellcome Mental Health Data Prize has chosen an unusual (for the research world) approach this time, using a “Dragon’s Den” style scheme where research teams can pitch their ideas to win funding for their projects.</description></item><item><title>Semantic text matching with deep learning Transformer models</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-02-08-semantic-text-matching-with-deep-learning-transformer-models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 22:36:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-02-08-semantic-text-matching-with-deep-learning-transformer-models/</guid><description>Semantic text matching is a task in natural language processing involving estimating the semantic similarity between two texts. For example, if we had to quantify the similarity between “I feel nervous” and “I feel anxious”, most people would agree that these are closer together than either sentence is to “I feel happy”. A semantic text matching algorithm would be able to place a number on the similarity, such as 79%.</description></item><item><title>Measuring the Performance of NLP algorithms</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-12-03-measuring-the-performance-of-nlp-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 01:19:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-12-03-measuring-the-performance-of-nlp-algorithms/</guid><description>Harmony was able to reconstruct the matches of the questionnaire harmonisation tool developed by McElroy et al in 2020 with the following AUC scores: childhood 84%, adulthood 80%. Harmony was able to match the questions of the English and Portuguese GAD-7 instruments with AUC 100% and the Portuguese CBCL and SDQ with AUC 89%. Harmony was also evaluated using a variety of transformer models including MentalBERT, a publicly available pretrained language model for the mental healthcare domain.</description></item><item><title>Harmony Questionnaire</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-10-harmony-questionnaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 19:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-10-harmony-questionnaire/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Back to the Future – Retrospectively Harmonizing Questionnaire Data</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-10-back-to-the-future-retrospectively-harmonizing-questionnaire-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-10-back-to-the-future-retrospectively-harmonizing-questionnaire-data/</guid><description>Now more than ever, the international research community are keen to determine whether their findings replicate across different contexts. For instance, if a researcher discovers a potentially important association between two variables, they may wish to see whether this association is present in other populations (e.g. different countries, or different generations). In an ideal world, this would be achieved by conducting follow-up studies that are harmonized by design. In other words, the exact same methodologies and measures would be used in a new sample, in order to determine whether the findings can be replicated.</description></item><item><title>PPIE for secondary data analysis</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-09-ppie-for-secondary-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 21:01:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-09-ppie-for-secondary-data-analysis/</guid><description>New Discoveries for Patient and Public Involvement
About one year ago I fully entered the world of secondary data analysis research – away from applied mental health research with creative data collection methods and small sample sizes, towards big data and complex analyses efforts to overcome what someone deemed not worth measuring (Wait, why are we not assessing emotion regulation in each and every study 1?)
Of course, I know we can’t measure everything and the decision of what to measure in studies is one of the hardest to make.</description></item><item><title>How does Harmony work?</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-03-how-does-harmony-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 14:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-03-how-does-harmony-work/</guid><description>When you input two questionnaires into Harmony, such as the GAD-7 and Beck’s Anxiety Inventory, Harmony is able to match similar questions and assign a number to the match. (I have written another blog post on how we measured Harmony’s performance in terms of AUC).
So how does Harmony achieve this?
Harmony uses techniques from the field of natural language processing to identify when two questions deal with a similar topic.</description></item><item><title>How to harmonise questionnaire data with Harmony (video)</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-10-25-harmonise-questionnaire-data-harmony-video/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 15:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-10-25-harmonise-questionnaire-data-harmony-video/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>