<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bettina Moltrecht on Harmony</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/author/bettina-moltrecht/</link><description>Recent content in Bettina Moltrecht on Harmony</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 14:31:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harmonydata.github.io/website/author/bettina-moltrecht/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Harmony going forward</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-03-10-harmony-going-forward-5-things-implementation-science-has-taught-us-to-focus-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 14:31:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2023-03-10-harmony-going-forward-5-things-implementation-science-has-taught-us-to-focus-on/</guid><description>5 key things Implementation Science has taught us to focus on
Yesterday the Harmony team received the wonderful news that we are given the chance to continue working on Harmony for another six months, after which we can put ourselves forward for the final round. The Wellcome Mental Health Data Prize has chosen an unusual (for the research world) approach this time, using a “Dragon’s Den” style scheme where research teams can pitch their ideas to win funding for their projects.</description></item><item><title>PPIE for secondary data analysis</title><link>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-09-ppie-for-secondary-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 21:01:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmonydata.github.io/website/post/2022-11-09-ppie-for-secondary-data-analysis/</guid><description>New Discoveries for Patient and Public Involvement
About one year ago I fully entered the world of secondary data analysis research – away from applied mental health research with creative data collection methods and small sample sizes, towards big data and complex analyses efforts to overcome what someone deemed not worth measuring (Wait, why are we not assessing emotion regulation in each and every study 1?)
Of course, I know we can’t measure everything and the decision of what to measure in studies is one of the hardest to make.</description></item></channel></rss>